快点 乔 擦亮点
Come on, Joe. Buff that sucker.
我怎么教你的
What'd I teach you?
真卫生
Sanitary.
乔是要在1940年的火车站里找工作吗
Is Joe applying for a job in a train station in 1940?
我只是在教他些每个男人都该知道的事情
Just teaching him a few things every man should know.
总得有人早点开始教
Someone has to get in there early,
不然有时候孩子会变得很滑稽
or sometimes the kid turns out funny.
我来了
Knock, knock.
-菲尔 -大家好啊
- Hey, Phil. - Hey, guys.
菲尔 过来
Phil, in here!
你准备好搞定你的网站了吗
You ready to tackle your website?
我知道我来早了点
I know I'm here a little early.
我想我要...
I thought I was gonna be --
你能尝出来吗
Do you recognize that?
开玩笑吗 我爱死你的酱了
Are you kidding? I love your sauce.
昨天晚上吃卷饼不小心洒了一点
Some of it fell out of my burrito last night,
洒到遥控器上 我都给舔干净了
and I licked it right off the remote.
那是爱丽丝姑妈新推出的酱
That's Auntie Alice's new sauce!
她偷了我的配方
She stole my recipe!
我知道
I know.
我是个动不动就暴走
I am the crazy Colombian that always loses her temper
需要被白人安抚情绪的疯狂哥伦比亚人
and needs to be calmed down by the white people.
不 我觉得你还不够疯
No! I don't think you're being crazy enough.
我不是个暴力的人 但我知道创作出特别的东西
I'm not a violent man, but I know how nuts it can make you
结果却被人偷了 是多么让人生气的事情
to create something special only to have it stolen from you.
你记得有首特别火的歌叫《Happy》吗
Do you remember a hit song called "Happy"?
记得啊 几年前出的吧
Yeah, it was like a couple of years ago
鼓掌啊 戴帽子的那个
with the clapping and the hat.
几年前吗
A couple of years ago, huh?
在这个出现整整四年后才出的
So a full four years after this burst on the scene.
*今儿个我倍儿爽*
*Because I'm snappy*
*如果今天很顺利 来和我一起爽*
*Snap with me if you think that today is a good day*
*没错 今儿个我倍儿爽*
*That's right, I'm snappy*
*如果今天考了满分 来和我一起爽*
*Snap with me if you took a test and you got an A*
*没错 今儿个我倍儿爽*
*You see, I'm snappy*
听着有点像 对吧
Sounds just a little similar, right?
-有点 但是... -谢谢
- A little, but -- Thank you!
但你觉得他看过这个吗
But do you think that he saw this?
点击量有27呢
Um, it had 27 views.
拜托 我们要去集市上
Come on. We're going down to that market
让那个老女人住手
to make that old bat cease and desist.
爱丽丝姑妈像法瑞尔·威廉姆斯
I will not stand idly by
那样剽窃你的作品 我可不能袖手旁观
while Auntie Alice Pharrell Williamses you.
你们俩要去哪里
Where are you two going?
去集市
To the market.
我们需要橄榄[配马丁尼]
We need olives!
灯关掉以后 她就会看到
And then when the lights go out, she'll be able to read
你T恤上的荧光墨迹
the glow-in-the-dark ink on your T-shirt.
-天哪 她会爱死的 -她 说谁呢
- Oh, my God. She's gonna love it. - She? Who's she?
你们俩在干什么呢
What are you guys working on?
-没什么 -没什么
- Nothing. - Nothing.
好吧 我懂了
Oh, okay. I get it, yeah.
他...我去卧室吧
He's -- I'll just be down in the bedroom, you know,
就...就走廊尽头那个
at the end of the -- at the end of the hall.
谢谢你帮我
Hey, thanks for your help.
我真的很喜欢那姑娘
I really like this girl,
请女孩子参加毕业舞会
and there's just so much pressure
总要做点什么特别的 简直太有压力了
to do something spectacular when you ask a girl out to prom.
你家的通风机有问题吗
Is there something wrong with your air vents?
没有 小卡偷听时就会用鼻子呼吸
No, Cam breathes through his nose when he hides.
邀请人参加毕业舞会 谁呀 劳利·沃克吗
A promposal? To who? Laurie Vock?
不会的 她被伊恩·雅各布请去了
Oh, no. She's Ian Jacobs' girl.
梅兰妮·瑞兰斯吗 她你可得小心点
Melanie Rylance? You have to be careful with her.
她的唇疱疹比艾比·布梅斯特还多
She has more cold sores than Abby Burmeister.
不过说真的 卢克 你在这里说的任何东西
But seriously, Luke, everything you say here
都是绝对保密的
is completely confidential.
他们都在找舞伴参加毕业舞会
Oh, you know, they are looking for chaperones for prom,
-我想也许我们可以 -不行
- and I thought maybe we could -- No, no.
我们那天晚上还要去看《卡巴莱》呢
We have tickets to the opening of "Cabaret" that night.
我才不要为了让某些十多岁的小姑娘别脱裙子
I'm not missing it so I can tell some teenage girl
而错过这个音乐剧
to keep her dress on.
我自己的毕业舞会就是那样干的
I spent my own prom doing that.
好吧 我能提一嘴你请教那个舅舅
Okay, can I just point out the absurdity
而不是这个 有多么荒谬吗
that you ask this uncle to advise you and not this uncle,
我曾在他办公室外挂了条情人节横幅上面写着
who hung a Valentine's banner outside of his office that said,
米奇尔 你是最好的丈夫 父亲和爱人
"Mitchell, you're the best husband, father, and lover."
我不喜欢这三个称呼放在同一个句子里
Didn't love all three of those being rolled into one sentence.
听着像奥扎克人说的
Sounded a little Ozark-y.
-小卡 住手 -怎么了
- No, Cam. Stop. - What?
卢克只是想请教一个
Luke's just looking for an adviser
简单朴素点
who's a little more understated
同时也没那么...你懂的
and a little less, you know...
大卫·斯图尔特的人
David Stuart.
我懂了
Oh, I get it.
-他挺基的 -我知道
- He's quite gay. - Yes, I got it.
好吧 知道吗
Okay, well, you know what?
我也不想让我的天分和派头
I would hate to muck up your promposal
毁了你的毕业舞会邀请
with my flair and panache.
我相信那个幸运的姑娘看到你用芥末酱
I'm sure the lucky girl will swoon with delight
在她的火鸡汉堡上
when you use a mustard bottle
写"想去吗"时 会幸福得晕过去的
to write "Wanna go?" On her turkey burger.
你好
Hello?
有人闯进家里了
There's an intruder in the house.
什么
What?!
但是有了普里契特3000卫士衣柜
But you have nothing to worry about
升级为军用级安全室
with Pritchett's Guardian 3000 Closet,
你就无需担心
which doubles as a military-grade panic room.
-所以没人闯进来吗 -没有
- So no intruder? - No!
就是这个创意让我很激动
I'm just so excited about this idea.
我下周要在橱柜大会上展示一下
I'm debuting it next week at ClosetCon.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
我觉得我在准备期末考呢
I think I'm studying for finals.
你就不能不吓我吗
Can't you scare the crap out of a focus group?
我要在北美最万众瞩目的
Like I'm gonna share my best closet idea
储物大会四天前
with a room full of strangers
在一屋子的陌生人面前
four days before the most hotly anticipated
展示我最棒的橱柜创意
storage convention in North America.
很好 你有海莉的号码吧
Good point. You do have Haley's number, right?
*第一次见到你的时候*
*From the first time that I saw your face*
*就已经知道你是我的真命天女*
*I knew you could be mine*
艾丽克斯·邓菲 你愿意让我成为全校最幸福的人
Alex Dunphy, would you make me the happiest cat in school
跟我在毕业舞会上摇摆吗
and swing by prom with me?
才...不要
Sha-Na-nope.
杰瑞 不知道为什么我用不了我的电脑了
Hey, Jerry. For some reason, I'm locked out of my computer.
很明显 有人在我用之前
Apparently, someone tried to access my e-mail
试图打开我的邮箱
before I got in.
有人想泄露公司机密
Someone hell-bent on leaking company secrets.
还有四天就是橱柜大会了 普里契特橱柜居然有内奸
It is four days until C-Con, and Pritchett's Closets has a mole.
所有人都有嫌疑
No one is above suspicion.
玛格瑞特 你今天早上9点45分的时候在哪里
Margaret, where were you this morning at 9:45 a.m.?
对不起我迟到了
I'm so sorry I was late.
我去参加暴食匿名互戒会了
I was at Overeaters Anonymous.
我又吃着冰激凌睡着了
I woke up next to the ice cream again.
所以不是玛格瑞特
So not Margaret.
我知道那个柜子是谁的
I know who that locker belongs to.
难以置信你居然要请那个贱霍[货]参加毕业舞会
I can't believe you're asking that cheap Ho to the prom.
-小卡 -萨拉·霍
- Cam! - Sarah Ho!
她在教师节给了我个5元的礼物券
She gave me a $5 gift card for Teacher Appreciation Day.
那些鸟是要干嘛
What's with the birds?
给曼尼邀请舞伴准备的斑鸠
Oh, these are just some turtledoves for Manny's promposal.
你开玩笑呢吧
You're joking.
卢克找我帮忙让你感觉被轻视了
You felt so slighted over Luke asking me
你就跑去逼曼尼了吗
that you foisted yourself on Manny?
我才没有逼他
There was no foisting.
我问曼尼需要帮忙吗
I asked Manny if he needed help.
他太傲慢了不肯承认 所以就这样了
He was too proud to admit that he did, so here we are.
你是不是在这个毕业舞会这件事上
Is it possible there's something deeper going on with you
有什么不可告人的秘密啊
around this whole prom area?
你是不是在后悔没准备点
Is it possible you're second-guessing
浪漫点的招啊
your no-frills approach?
特别比起斑鸠啊 伴舞啊
Especially compared to turtledoves, backup dancers,
还有干冰 可以让曼尼在一片迷雾中出场
and dry ice so Manny can appear in a cloud of mist.
一片迷雾
A cloud of mist?
像电影里那样吗
Like in a movie?
我们的创意会不会有点弱了
Is our thing gonna seem lame now?
淡定
Steady.
好了 我觉得你们的创意还是可以的
Now, now. I'm sure your thing is fine.
看看你们柜子上便条写着啥
What did your little locker note say?
"去体育馆"
"Go to the gym."
很神秘哟
Intriguing.
体育馆会有什么惊喜等着她呢
What delights await her in the gym?
另一张指示她去停车场的便条
Another note telling her to go to the parking lot.
我还是去帮曼尼准备好吧
Well, I should help Manny set up.
我是不是该慌了呢
Should I be worried?
别在这会儿吓我好吧
Don't freak me out right now, okay?
-好吧 -没事的 不会有事
- Okay. All right. - It's fine. Just fine.
你们不一定用得上它 但是起码先拿着
You don't have to use it, but at least you'll have it.
你好 爱丽丝姑妈
Hello, Auntie Alice.
还是爱你死姑妈
Or should she say Auntie Malice?
不 歌洛莉亚说对了 是爱丽丝
No, Gloria's right. It's Alice.
我不知道你今天也进场卖酱
I didn't know you were in today.
你惹上大麻烦了
You're in -- trouble!
他没事吧
Is he okay?
-你偷了我的酱料配方 -什么
- You stole my sauce! - What?
不好意思 可能你的耳朵有点背了
Uh, I'm sorry. Maybe you don't hear so good.
她说的是 "你偷了她的酱料配方"
She said, "You...stole... her...sauce."
这酱好辣
That's spicy.
这不是她剽窃的那种酱
That's not the sauce she stole.
那是她的火山酱料
That's her Volcano sauce.
广告里一滴酱就能让曲棍球冰场变成大泳池
In her ad, one drop turns a hockey rink into a swimming pool.
是她新出的那款酱尝着跟我的一模一样
It's her new sauce, the one that tastes just like mine.
你要怎么解释
How are you going to explain that?
对 我们需要解释 再来点面包
Yeah, we want answers and a little bread.
你们不该跟我吵
Your fight's not with me.
我不是真的爱丽丝姑妈
I'm not really Auntie Alice.
得了吧
Oh, come on.
你的小脸蛋就印在瓶子上
Your cute face is in the bottle!
"爱丽丝姑妈"是一间大公司旗下的品牌
Auntie Alice is a brand that was created by a big corporation.
所以是这间公司的人偷了我的配方
So they were the ones who stole my sauce?
他们什么产品都剽窃偷用
They steal all kinds of products.
他们还有一团队的律师
And they have an army of lawyers
专门打压跟他们对着干的人
just ready to crush anyone who challenges them.
那我们只能逆来顺受吗
So we just have to take it?
弄到我眼睛里了 天哪
It's in my eye! Oh!
请别把我这事说出去 不然我会失业的
Please don't repeat any of this, or I could lose my job.
我艺术班的学费还没交完呢
I'm still paying off my improv classes.
这么辣怎么能让人吃呢
How is this food?!
这车以后很可能是你的了
This will probably be yours someday,
所以你没有理由不学换机油
so no reason you shouldn't learn to do this.
曼尼知道该怎么换油吗
Does Manny know how to change oil?
-他会换沐浴精油 -什么是沐浴精油
- Bath oils. - What? Bath oil?
果然是我儿子
There's my guy.
把油尺给我
Let me grab the dipstick.
这根吗
This stick?
曼尼 我已经交代好其他人了
Manny. Okay. I just briefed the team.
干冰准备好了 领结放在鸟身上
Dry ice is ready. Bow ties are on the birds.
别费力了 小卡
Save it, Cam.
梅根已经答应肖恩·里弗斯了
Megan already said yes to Shawn Reeves.
他上个课间问她的
He asked her last period.
那可真遗憾 曼尼
Oh, I'm so sorry, Manny.
其实也不能怪她
Can't really blame her.
谁会傻到拒绝肖恩·里弗斯
I mean, you try saying no to Shawn Reeves
他那气象播报员微笑和迷人加拿大口音呢
with his weatherman smile and his exotic Canadian accent.
肯定还有别的姑娘可以做你的舞伴
Well, there must be someone else you can ask.
不用了 没事 反正每年都有机会
No, that's okay. There's always next year.
起码这样我还能看开场的《歌厅》
At least this way I can see the opening of "Cabaret".
拜托 只是《歌厅》而已
Oh, please. It's just "Cabaret."
迪克·切尼被救活的次数都没有这部剧多
It's been revived more times than Dick Cheney.
行了 你不能错过你的毕业舞会
Okay. You're not missing your prom.
小卡 其实我感觉
Cam... I'm getting the feeling
你比我还看重我的舞会
this is much more important to you than it is to me.
好吧 可能是因为我自己的没去成
Well, maybe because I didn't get to go to mine.
真遗憾
Oh. I'm sorry.
对 这是一个悲伤的故事
Yeah, it's a painful story.
我懂 有些事还是不说为好
I get it. Some things are better left unsaid.
她的名字叫迪娜·黛
Her name was Tina Day.
我们只是朋友 但我很想邀请她共舞
We were just friends, but I was so into asking her,
我甚至还租了一匹白马和一套铠甲
I rented a white stallion and a suit of armor.
想营造出《危情谍战》里的氛围
I wanted it to be a whole "Knight and Day" Theme.
远在舞会之前 我就向她发出邀请了
I was promposing before it was even a thing.
我骑马骑到她家门口的车道上
I rode up her driveway,
透过我头盔的缝隙
and I could see when she opened the door
看着她开门的时候
through the little slits in my helmet
我就知道她的回答是什么了
what her answer was gonna be.
她想和一个能让她失身的男生一起
She wanted a traditional prom night with a guy
享受一个传统的毕业舞会之夜
she could lose her virginity to.
我不能怪她
I couldn't blame her.
我也渴望这么一个男生
I wanted the same thing.
毕业舞会的女伴还有不少人选
There's always Melanie Rylance,
但是你可别想让我去邀请
but you wouldn't want me to ask someone --
伙计们 让舞者和鸽子炮就位
Delta, ready the dancers and dove cannon.
可怜的女士
Poor lady.
我真不该那样凶她
I feel terrible for screaming at her like that.
怪我
I blame myself.
我也怪你
I blame yourself, too.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我只是压力太大了
I'm just kind of going through something.
今天早上我参加莉莉的职业日
I got bumped from Lily's career day this morning
被一个牙周病医生比下去了
by a periodontist.
也对 我的职业是比不上烂牙根有意思
That's right. My job is less interesting that root rot.
三年级小学生的想法算什么
Who cares about a bunch of third graders?
你喜欢当房地产中介
You love being a real-estate agent.
首先 我不只是一个房地产中介
First of all, I'm not just a real-estate agent.
我是个房地产经纪人
I'm a Realtor.
我是全国协会的一员
I'm a member of a national association,
宣誓服从房地产经纪人道德规范的一分子
a brotherhood, sworn to the Realtor Code of Ethics!
这上面的"徽"就象征了我的身份
That's what this "R" Stands for.
虽然后来我觉得它更像是"悔"
Though, lately, it feels like it stands for "Regret".
关于房地产的一切我无不知晓
I know everything there is to know about real estate,
然而这并没有什么用
and nobody seems to care.
也许我的职业是世界上最无聊的
Maybe I have the most boring job in the world.
不 菲尔
No, Phil.
做衣柜生意才是世界上最无聊的
Closets is the most boring job in the world.
可怜的人
Ay, poor thing.
她还要等公车
She has to take the bus.
我们捎她一段吧
Let's offer her a ride.
行 行
Yes, yes.
她开玛莎拉蒂
A Maserati?
她骗了我们
She lied to us!
不 我是叫你"跟上她"
No, that means "Follow her."
-你好 -妈妈
- Hello? - Hey, Mom.
门前草坪上的洒水器怎么打开
How do you turn on the sprinklers for the front lawn?
在大门旁边有个小的控制盒 怎么了
Uh, it's a little control box by the front door. Why?
没什么
No reason.
听着 既然你打给我了
Look, now that I've got you on the phone,
我想说我们是不是该提高网络安全等级了
I'm thinking it might be time to upgrade our Internet security.
该怎么做呢
Thoughts?
先撕掉那张粘在你电脑上的
Get rid of the Post-it note on your laptop
写着你密码的便利贴
with your password on it.
你怎么担心起网络安全了
Why are you so worried about security?
这是我第一次以总裁身份参加会议
It's my first ClosetCon as C.E.O.,
而且我发现公司里有间谍
and I am dealing with corporate espionage.
如果你真这么担心
Well, if you're so worried about it,
为什么不直接打给外公呢
why don't you just call Grandpa?
你知道那会多糗吗
Do you know how that would look?
去找你职位的前任寻求帮助
I mean, it's bad enough to go to the person
已经够难堪的了
who had your job before you,
更别提如果这个人是你爸的话
but when that person is daddy...
宝贝 做衣柜生意的人都是冷酷无情的
Honey, closet people are ruthless.
他们会把我生吞活剥的
They'd eat me alive.
也可能这个世界上并不全是冷血怪物
Or maybe the world isn't filled with heartless monsters.
我手机被淋湿了
My phone is wet.
你能打个电话给我妈妈吗
Can you call my mom?
大家好 抱歉我来晚了
Hey, guys. Sorry I'm late.
刚刚才跟"宅在架"公司的
I just got off the horn
瑞克·弗莱德曼通完电话
with Rick Friedman over at Shelf Involved.
可怜的人啊
That poor guy.
他们那儿有人将公司机密泄露了出去
Someone there has given away corporate secrets.
还好我们公司刚刚升级过安保系统
Makes me so glad that we just upgraded our whole security system.
我的意思是 公司楼里藏了些摄像头
I mean, we got hidden cameras around this place
连我都不知道在哪
that I don't even know about.
所以 我们为玛格丽特的生日买了蛋糕
So, we got a cake for Margaret's birthday.
很好
Fun.
你最近如何 本
How you doing, Ben?
我吗 我很好 我很好
Me? I'm good. I am good.
我有点冷
I am chill.
我要去趟洗手间 失陪一下
I'm gonna go to the bathroom, so...
其实今天不是我生日
It's not really my birthday.
我只是想吃蛋糕
I just wanted cake.
我吃垃圾因为我就是个垃圾
I eat garbage because I am garbage.
老爸
Hey, Dad. Hi.
听着 我能等会儿打给你吗
Um, listen. Can I call you back?
我就是确认下晚餐我们一起去...
Just wanted to confirm we're on for dinner at --
另一个电话来了 等等别挂
Oh, got another call. One sec.
我觉得她开始怀疑我们了
Yeah, I think she's onto us.
是的 各种吓唬人的暗示
Yeah, a lot of mole talk.
我认为我们要避避风头...
I think we just need to calm things d--
什么
What?
你刚在和她打电话吗
You're talking to her right now?
好吧 拜拜
Yeah, okay, bye.
所以 今晚出去吃饭
So, we're on for tonight?
-没问题 -很好
- Sure. - Great.
还有 你听起来有点紧张
And, hey, you sound a little tense.
别被工作逼成个疯婆子 好吗
Don't let the job make you crazy, huh?
压力一大 你看啥都是阴谋
You go that route, soon you're seeing plots everywhere.
好建议 老爸
Great tip, Dad.
你在为我爸当间谍
You're spying for my dad!
什么 我没有 好吧 对不起
What? No! Yes. I'm sorry.
我不知道自己为什么同意
I don't know why I agreed.
我只是太仰慕你父亲了
I just look up to your dad so much.
我真不敢相信他不相信我
I can't believe he doesn't trust me.
那他为什么还让我掌管公司
Why did he put me in charge, then?
我不知道 但我能找到原因
I don't know, but I can find out.
我可以当双面间谍
I'll double-agent.
从我父母离婚时起 我就一直从事间谍工作
I've been working this game since my parents' divorce.
我是纽约大颈区唯一一个没有
I was the only 10-year-old in Great Neck
睡前故事和信用卡的十岁小孩
with no bedtime and Diners Club card.
够了 你今晚什么事都别安排
Fine. Don't make any plans for tonight.
跟我一起去家庭聚餐
You're coming to dinner with me.
行 我们能顺道去一趟我家让我换双鞋吗
All right. Um, can we stop by my house to change my shoes?
我刚才第一次上马桶时滑了下
I didn't make it up here on the first try.
好了 鸽子加农炮装载完毕
All right, the dove cannon's loaded,
舞者们都在热身 干冰如雾般翻滚
the dancers are stretching, the dry ice is billowing.
你将她带出去的一刹那 我会给小队使暗号
The moment you get her outside, I will cue the team.
她来了
Oh, there she is.
走起
Okay. Go.
注意 队员们 注意着点
All right, team. Look alive.
行动开始 行动开始
We are hot. We are hot.
-你好 梅兰妮 听着 -曼尼
- Hey, Melanie. Listen -- - Manny.
你愿意和我一起参加毕业舞会吗
Do you want to go to prom with me?
当然
Uh, sure.
你有时间[第二名]吗
You got a second?
当然
Yeah.
是啊 我是第二名 你是第一名
Yeah, I'm second. You're first.
我懂了 你什么都是赢家
I get it. You win everything.
听起来好像发生了些什么我不知道的
That seems like something I'm gonna hear about later.
卢克的"舞伴请帖"需要人帮忙
I need help with Luke's promposal, okay?
你能去趟健身房 等莎拉来 然后交给她吗
Can you go to the gym, wait for Sarah, and then hand her this?
我已经沦落到干这种事了吗
Okay, this is what I've been reduced to?
像个信差似的 派送一封连香水都没喷的请帖 没问题
Delivering an unperfumed envelope like a common bellhop? Fine.
谢谢 拜托了
Thank you. Okay.
解除戒备 所有人员
Stand down, everybody.
小熊精已修得正果
Little Bear's gone rogue.
等等
Wait.
格雷森 你好啊
Grayson! Hey.
-你好 教练 -你好
- Hey, Coach. - Hey.
不用想也知道 你正计划邀请某人去参加舞会
Don't suppose you're planning on asking anyone to prom.
我觉得学校不允许请老师当舞伴
Um, I don't think we're allowed to go with teachers.
我不是这个意思...
That's not what...
看来这就是那个"偷酱贼"的老巢
So, this is the house that stolen sauce built.
我气炸了 都不知道该对她说什么了
I'm so angry that I don't even know what I'm gonna say to her!
看来这就是那个"偷酱贼"的老巢
Ah, so, this is the house that the stolen sauce built!
我知道你们怎么想 但这不是我的房子
Oh, I know what you're thinking, but this isn't my house.
我只是过来拿我的工资
I just come here to get my paycheck.
奶奶 我的淋浴头坏了
Grandma, my shower's broken.
我去客房那个淋浴间洗澡
I'm gonna use the one in the guesthouse.
请当我的钢琴老师吧
Please be my new piano teacher.
我招了
Fine.
我就是爱丽丝姑妈
I'm Auntie Alice.
"盗窃姑妈"还有"谎言姑妈"
Auntie Thief and Auntie Liar.
没错 没错
Yeah, yeah.
我相信我们会有到解决方法的
I'm sure we can work something out.
谁是你的专利律师
Who's your patent lawyer?
我没有律师
I don't have one.
我就知道
I know.
今早我已经将你的酱申请专利了
I patented your sauce this morning.
回家旅途愉快 孩子们
Have a good trip home, kids.
我真的非常抱歉 菲尔 浪费了你一整天时间
I am so sorry, Phil, that I wasted your whole day,
但我更抱歉的是 我马上要对你车做的事
but I am more sorry of what I'm gonna do to your car!
歌洛莉亚 我们大人有大量
Gloria, we're above that.
不是所有人都有这肚量
But not everyone would be.
你该把你的豪车停在车库里
You should put that beauty in your garage.
-我没有车库 -哦 是吗
- I don't have one. - Oh, really?
好奇问一句 你没有车库是因为
Just out of curiosity, do you not have a garage
你把车库改造成了客房
because you converted it into the guesthouse
那个你孙子正在洗澡的地方吗
where your grandson's currently showering?
你在耍什么花招 先生
What's your game, mister?
我只是很好奇你名下有
I just find it interesting that you have
一栋违法私自改造的独立住宅
a fully plumbed stand-alone dwelling on your property.
这不关你的事
That's none of your business.
更奇怪的是 似乎你的孙子也住在这
Even more peculiar, your grandson appears to live here,
但从他的T恤衫看 他在伊甸米尔斯高中上学
but judging by his T-shirt, he goes to Eden Mills High,
一所不属于本地区的精英公立学校
an elite public school 12 miles outside of your district.
也许你用在私立学校上省下的钱
Oh, maybe with the money you saved on private schools,
买了那我看到的新的双面砖壁炉
you paid for the new two-sided brick fireplace I saw,
那壁炉自1988年就已被明令禁止了
which hasn't been legal since 1988.
加油 菲尔 加油
Go, Phil, go!
酱紫你还嘴硬吗 偷酱贼
Pull the sauce, Big Al,
否则星期一早晨 你家门前将会有一辆推土机
or Monday morning, the city's here with a bulldozer,
你的孙子将戴着金属探测器去学校
and your grandson goes to a school with a metal detector.
你是怎么知道这些的
How do you know all this?
你到底是做什么的 房地产中介人吗
What are you -- some kind of real-estate agent?
不 他是房产经纪人
No. He's a Realtor.
这是有区别的[其实没有]
There is a difference somehow!
嘿 孩子们
Oh, hey, kids.
实际上 我在等莎拉
Actually, I'm waiting for Sarah,
所以 如果你们能等一分钟再进来
so if I could have the room for just a -- a minute.
谢谢 好吧 真有趣
Thank -- Okay, funny.
不管是谁把灯关掉了 麻烦你打开好吗
Whoever turned out the lights, please turn them back on.
灯坏了 可能是保险丝烧了
They're not working. Might be a fuse.
米切尔 我们有问题了
Mitchell, we have a problem.
不 我们没有
No, we don't.
我是说 除非你那晚很忙
I mean, unless you're busy that night.
你...你是在邀请我去舞会吗
Are -- Are you asking me to prom?
你知道的 他们要求携舞伴
Well, you know, they need chaperones.
米切尔 这是你为我做的最浪漫的事了
Mitchell, this is the sweetest thing you've ever done for me.
我不知道我有没有提过
I-I don't know if I've mentioned it,
但我从没去过我自己的毕业舞会
but I never got to go to my own prom.
我想起来了
It's come up.
那卢克的"舞伴请帖"怎么办
What about Luke's promposal?
你老公我 这个即使拿枪架在头上逼着
Well, your husband, who couldn't plan anything romantic
都不能制造浪漫的人
with a gun to his head,
可能已经一石二鸟将两个"舞伴请帖"都搞定了
may have pulled off two promposals at once.
你知道是谁把那张便条放我柜子里了吗
Do you have any idea who put that note in my locker
问我是否愿意参加这活动的
asking me to be a part of this thing?
我知道 是我舅舅放的
Oh, yeah, it was my uncle.
他"把灯都关了" 实在是太聪明了
It's pretty clever how he turned out the lights.
我说"把灯都关了"
I said, "Turned out the lights"!
天啊 我愿意
Oh, my God! Yes!
好甜蜜啊 我...
That's so sweet. I...
我真不敢相信 我终于可以去参加高中舞会了
And I can't believe I'm finally going to prom.
我也不敢相信 我终于在高中体育馆
I can't believe I finally have a happy memory
拥有了一点美好的回忆
in a high-school gym.
-乔把你伤成这样的吗 -是啊
- Joe did that to you? - Yeah.
-他把引擎盖砸我手上了 -为什么
- Slammed a car hood on it. - Why?
我欠他钱呗
I owed him money.
是我在教他检查油箱时 引擎盖滑落了
It slipped while I was teaching him to check oil.
对个三岁小孩来说 那有点超前吧
Well, that's pretty advanced for a 3-year-old.
我能怎么说呢 我对我的孩子有信心
What can I say? I believe in my kids.
谢谢
Thank you.
看上去很棒 谢谢
Looks good. Thank you.
非常好
Very nice.
我们迅速来过一遍计划
Let's quickly go over the plan.
我爸随时都会到的
My dad's gonna be here any minute.
我们要一步一步来
We're doing this in stages.
我出一根手指 意味着你要给他发
One finger means you text him
"我们要把百叶窗部门撤掉"
"We're closing the blinds division."
那可是盈利最多的
Our biggest earner?
如果我跟他说要撤掉百叶窗部门 他会发疯的
He's gonna lose it if I tell him we're shuttering blinds.
两根手指 你就发"我们要跟罗德·布什米尔合作"
Two fingers, we're partnering with Rod Bushmill.
那个无赖代表了你父亲
That sleazebag represents everything
在整个职业生涯中所极力抵抗的一切东西
your father spent an entire career fighting against.
三根手指 你就发"我们不去参加衣柜展览大会了"
Three fingers, we're not going to ClosetCon. Wha--
你到底只是想给你爸一个教训
Are you trying to teach your father a lesson
还是磨灭他的灵魂
or crush his soul?
商场无情 小子
Just business, kid.
魔鬼
Monster.
看上去不错 谢谢
Looks good. Thank you.
鉴于高中舞会就快要举办了
So...with all this prom stuff coming up,
你家里是不是也跟我家里一样混乱
is your house as topsy-turvy as ours is?
不算吧 曼尼要带一个姑娘过去
Not really. Manny's taking this girl.
她也没什么特别的 就是挺靠谱的
She's nothing special, but solid.
很可靠
Reliable.
跟我们的百叶窗部门很像
A lot like our blinds division.
虽然不性感 但是...
You know -- not sexy, but --
别 爸 别谈公事
No, Dad. No shop talk.
你已经谈了一辈子工作了
You've had enough of that for a lifetime.
今晚你的手机还真忙啊
Wow, your phone is really blowing up tonight.
两杯老式鸡尾酒
Two old-fashioneds.
-谢谢 -谢谢
- Thank you. - Oh, thank you.
好的 给
Okay. Here.
你觉得现在还有什么是我觉得很老式的吗
You know what else seems old-fashioned to me nowadays?
-什么 -正直
- Mm? - Integrity.
或许我的整个职业生涯
Maybe because I spent my career
都在跟行业里的无赖抗争
fighting the sleazeballs in our industry.
就是罗德·布什米尔那一类的
You know -- the Rod Bushmill types.
罗德真是个好人
Rod's a sweetheart.
他上周请我吃午餐了
He bought me lunch last week.
我们谈论了一下是否该...
We got to talking about whether or not we --
我这是在干什么呢
What am I doing?
唠叨着工作上的事
Jibber-jabbering about work.
乔那个小恶魔才三岁
So, that little grease monkey Joe is 3.
真不敢相信 三岁啊
Hard to believe. 3.
小孩子长得可真快啊
They grow up so fast.
不过这种感觉一定很好吧 爸
Got to be nice, though, Dad,
你的公司被我运营得很好
knowing that your company is in good hands
你可以安心在家里整天带小孩玩
and you can stay home all day long and just play with your kid.
你是疯了吗
Have you lost your mind?
当然了 也不是玩一整天
Well, not all day, obviously.
三岁的小孩就是狂躁不安的小细菌罐
3-year-olds are nothing but bipolar germ buckets.
你不去参加衣柜展会了吗
You're skipping out on ClosetCon?
-谁告诉你的 -本
- Who told you that? - Ben.
那个小内奸把什么都告诉我了
That little weasel told me everything.
听着 我可以容忍你关停百叶窗部门
Listen, I can tolerate shutting down the blinds,
甚至是和罗德·布什米尔合作 但不去参加衣柜展会
even Rod Bushmill, but not showing up for ClosetCon,
你就是明摆着让别人来轻视你
you're asking not to be taken seriously.
天啊 克莱尔
My God, Claire!
我们只要再迎来一个强势售卖季 就可以获邀
We're one strong season away from being invited
参加衣柜世博会了
to Expo Internationale du Closets!
你为什么这样看着我
Why are you looking at me like that?
因为我并没有做那些事
'Cause I'm not doing any of those things.
我让那个小内奸本故意给你发这些信息
I told that little weasel Ben to text you those things
因为我发现他是你安插的小间谍
when I found out that he was spying for you.
顺便说下 当我知道你不信任我
And, by the way, it doesn't feel very nice
可以运营好你的公司 那种感觉并不好受
to know that you don't think that I can run your company.
那不是我这么做的原因
That's not why I did it.
我心想着 或许你需要一点支持
I thought maybe you could use a little support.
你的准备工作做得还不够好
You're staring down the barrel of your first ClosetCon.
所以你就派人监视我吗
So you spied on me?
你可以给我打个电话的啊
I mean, you could have given me a call.
然后告诉你 你工作做得不好吗
And tell you that you're not doing your job?
说得好像你能接受似的
That would have gone over fine with you.
需要帮助吗
Need any help?
-不需要 -不需要
- No! - No.
瞧瞧我们
I mean, look at us.
我们怎么就不能都承认
Why can't we both admit
我们现在需要彼此的帮助呢
that we could use each other's help right now?
难道我们太高傲了 连这都不愿意吗
Are we too proud to even do that?
如果你承认 我就承认
I'll admit it if you will.
好吧 数到三
Fine. On 3.
-你能帮我破开龙虾吗 -我想回去工作
- Will you crack my lobster? - I want to come back to work.
-什么 -该死的
- What?! - Damn it!
天啊 你竟然想回去工作
Oh, my God. You want to come back to work?
我很想念那种感觉
I miss it, okay?
你明白对衣柜行业的热爱深入血液是什么感觉
You know how it is when you have closets in your blood.
我退休后都快要疯了
I'm going crazy in retirement.
你为什么要对我露出这样的笑容
Why are you smiling at me like that?
因为我们父女俩太像了
Because we're so similar.
你知道我有多少次想给你打电话
Do you know how many times I've wanted to call you
向你寻求帮助或建议
to ask for your help or advice,
但我却害怕让自己显得很弱吗
but I was afraid I would look weak?
给 你帮我破开
Here. You crack this.
-给我 -我来剥这些
- Give me that. - I'll open these things.
爸 你想回来工作吗
Well, Dad, what do you think about coming back to work --
比如 每周工作一两天怎么样
I don't know -- one or two days a week?
我的想法是 给我5名员工
What I was thinking was, I'd have a staff of five.
-给我一栋独立办公楼 -什么
- My own building. - What?
并且不要给我安排任何上级
And I report to no one.
我开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
我在打印室放张桌子就行了
I'll put a desk in the copy room.
顺便说下 我对你有很深的了解
And, by the way, I've known you for a long time.
你最不需要担心的 就是显得很弱
The last thing you need to worry about is looking weak.
向别人开口寻求你想要的东西并不容易
It's not always easy to ask for what you want,
不管是一点点浪漫
whether it's a little romance...
一点点帮助
or a little help...
还是一点点尊重
or a little respect.
-所以我很欣赏你们开口... -我不
- So, I admire you for asking -- - I don't.
我们都知道他们的目的
We both know why they're asking.
不行 你们不能用我们家楼上公寓开余兴派对
No, you may not use our upstairs apartment for an after party.
真挫
Lame.
你看上去令人迷醉 亲爱的
You look ravishing, my sweet.
我们说好了不交谈的
We said no talking.
-来 再来 -我好渴
- Come on. Come on. - I'm thirsty.
我来决定你什么时候才是真的渴
I'll tell you when you're thirsty.
来 让我感受到你的力量
Come on. Let me feel that power.
来 把皮手套打得爆响吧
Come on. Make that leather sing!
好了 骑车去
All right. Come on. Get on your bike.
退后 上车 快
Back up. Get on your bike. Come on.
如果他们抓不到你 就打不到你
They can't hit you if they can't reach you.
我的裤子要掉了
My pants are falling.
拉起来啊
Well, pull 'em up.
拉到胸部去
Pull 'em up high to your nipples.
那样就能避免"爆蛋"了
That prevents a low blow.
"爆蛋"是什么
What's a low blow?
好极了
Fantastic.
我明天要主持一个诗歌怀旧会
I have to emcee a poetry retrospective tomorrow,
但这件围巾领西装上的皱纹
and this shawl collar's got more wrinkles
比昨晚的《唐顿庄园》还要多
than last night's "Downton Abbey."
就是这样的
That is.